翻译 william268 ★放肆欧米嘎☆ Lucyna
校审 william2568 SUSTCer.Zen 鮈鱼 Lucyna
时间轴/微博@Emtee
好了
Okay.
好了 我知道 我知道
Okay. I know, I know.
抱歉 我知道我该轻点
I'm sorry, I know it's a little tender.
好了 现在试着发声
Okay. Let's try your voice now.
我叫凯特尼斯·艾佛丁  我家在12区
My name is Katniss Everdeen, I'm from District 12.
我
My
没事 慢慢来
Okay, take your time.
你的声带很肿胀
You got a lot of swelling in your vocal chords.
我
My
叫
name is
凯特尼斯
Katniss
艾佛丁
Everdeen.
我想
I want
我想跟他谈谈
I want to talk to him.
他需要时间
He needs time.
但是
But
今天让他见个新面孔
We're trying something new today.
见到那些医生时他情绪没什么变化 但是
He's been calmer with the doctors, but
他们对他来说是陌生人 所以
They are strangers to him, so
专家让他见几个家乡的熟人 来测试他的反应
They're going to test his responses someone he remembers from home.
他会见到一个你信赖的人
Someone you trust.
让她进去
Send her in.
嗨
Hey.
- 身体好些了吗 - 她走的太近了
- How're you doing? - She's too close.
没事的
It's okay.
我们现在在13区
We're in District 13 now.
13区是真实存在的 那些传言是真的
It's a real place. The stories are true.
我的家人没来看我
My family hasn't come to see me.
12区遭到了轰炸
There's an attack on 12.
我的家人
My family.
他们没能幸存下来
They didn't survive.
因为凯特尼斯
Because of Katniss.
- 就是因为她 - 那不是她的错
- It's because of Katniss. - It wasn't because of Katniss.
- 她告诉你这么说的 - 她什么都没告诉我
- She tell you to say that. - She didn't tell me anything.
普瑞姆 她是个骗子
She's a liar, Prim.
那是个诡计
It's a trick.
好吧
Yeah.
你所说的是假的
What you're saying isn't real.
她派你进来找我的
She sent you here to talk to me.
- 她知道你现在在这 - 没事的
- She knows you're here now. - It's okay.
她全都知道 你不能相信她
She knows. You can't trust her!
她是个怪物 是个混蛋
She's a monster! She's a mutt!
她是都城派来摧毁我们的
The Capitol bring her to destroy us!
把她带出来
Get her out of there.
你明白我说的话吗
Do you understand me!
普瑞姆 你一定要杀了她
You have to kill her, Prim!
你一定要.. 杀了她
You have to kill her!
- 凯特尼斯 - 她是个混蛋
- Katniss. - She's a mutt!
- 他只是受了药物的影响 - 杀了她
- This is just the condition responds. - Kill her!
- 那不是真正的他 - 她是个怪物 是个混蛋
- It's not him. - She's a monster! She's a mutt!
- 没错 那不是他 - 她是个混蛋
- No, it's not him. - She's a mutt!
饥饿游戏:嘲笑鸟(下)
请过来吧
Please, come in.
你们能离开一下吗
Will you excuse us?
- 一会儿就好 - 没问题
- For just a moment. - Of course.
请坐
Have a seat.
很高兴你身体有所好转
I'm glad you're feeling better.
斯诺要为他所犯下的罪行付出代价
Snow has to pay for what he's done.
我愿意全力跟你们合作
I want to help the rebels in any way I can.
看到皮塔那样真是难过
It's hard to see Peeta this way.
那不是他
That's not Peeta.
送我去都城区 我会尽我所能
Send me to the Capitol. I'll do anything.
对此我无能为力
I can't.
我不能把你送到那
I can't send you there.
在我们控制2区前我没法把你送到那
We can't get into the Capitol until we control District 2.
那就送我去2区
Then send me to 2.
你需要我鼓舞士气
You want me to fire up our troops.
振奋军心 我到那边看看我能做些什么
Call out to the loyalists, I'll see what I can do.
是的 你在那会很有用的
Yes, that'll help.
在我走之前
I saw Peeta
我去看望了皮塔
before we left.
有何想法?
What'd you think?
感到自己很自私
Something selfish.
因为你再也不用嫉妒他了吗
That you don't have to be jealous of him anymore?
不
No.
在他好转之前我肯定毫无机会
I don't stand a chance if he doesn't get better.
你肯定还是对他念念不忘
You'll never let him go.
你在想什么呢
What's going on in your head?
我不知道
I don't know.
这就像你与一个醉汉接吻
It's like kissing someone who's drunk.
那根本不是真正的吻
It doesn't count.
准备降落
Prepare for landing.
将它包上
Wrap it up.
最后一次机会 行动
Last chance. Go.
这个装置就像一个捕鸟夹
This is another bird and food trapping resource.
这部分装置使人致盲
This one is designed to blind,
烟雾遮住眼睛
the smoke clings to the eyes.
和你抓蜂鸟一个道理
That's an application for Hummingbird trap.
人们感到恐惧 开始跑向
You scared the people, so they flee in this direction
一个他们认为安全的方向
to what they think is a safe haven.
这时引爆炸药
Two tier explosion.
再过会 会有人冲上来帮助伤员
We'll have people enough time to rush in and help the wounded.
这时再次引爆
A second bomb.
没错
Right.
第二枚炸弹安放在这
Second one goes off here.
我想在战场上 为了杀掉另一个人
I guess there are no rules anymore
你们真是不择手段啊
about what a person can do to another person.
我觉得他们劫走皮塔时 可没有手下留情吧
I don't think some of them use any rule book when we hijacked Peeta.
欢迎来到2区
Welcome to District 2.
我是赫姆斯下士 请跟我来
I'm Corporal Homes. If you'll follow me, please.
不用担心
Don't worry.
政府军就是这么对我们说早安的
That's how the loyals say good morning.
科因总统 感谢您派来的增援部队
President Coin, we're indebted to you for the reinforcements
同时感谢嘲笑鸟对我们的帮助
and the Mockingjay.
但我们不确定2区以外的人是不是知道我们起义的消息
But I'm not sure that anyone outside of 2 knows what we've been up against.
这个是“坚果”的立体图
This is the Nut.
它是都城的设在2区的总部 也是我们行动的目标
The Capitol's headquarters for our offensive operations.
驻扎在里面的不仅有政府军 还有部分二区的平民
It's manned by both military and civilian personnel from District 2.
从地图上看 整个堡垒建在岩层深处
As you can see, the fortress lies so far beneath the bedrock,
易守难攻
it's untouchable.
昨天我们试图突破东北门
Yesterday, we attempted to take the northeastern gate.
接着遭到空中的进攻 不得不撤退
Then we encountered from higher up and we're forced to pull back.
损失惨重
We took heavy loses.
能不能策划一次佯攻 比如派部队聚集在其中一个门附近
Could we create a decoy? Send troops towards one of the gates
然后猛攻另一个
and just send an attack on another.
那么 指挥官你要把哪支部队当做诱饵派上前线呢
Well, who's troops do you propose as a decoy, Commander.
我们有嘲笑鸟 别低估了她的作用
We have the Mockingjay, don't underestimate her.
我们可以用她瓦解敌人内部
We could use her to erode support.
她也许能让某些政府军动摇
She maybe be able to sway some of the loyalists.
科因女士 你在地下工事里待了很长一段时间了
You've been underground a long time, Madam Coin.
这里和帕纳姆其它地方不一样
This isn't like the rest of Panem
在这 支持都城的大有人在
Support for the Capitol runs deep here.
那么这里确实是一块难啃的硬骨头
Then there's no sacrifice is too great.
我们需要占领堡垒内部的武器库
We need to control the arsenal inside that fortress.
即使我们全军出动 也显得人手不足
Even with every District and it's alliance, we're outgunned.
要是仅仅为了抢武器 我不会派我的地面部队进攻的
I won't commit my people to a ground assault,  just to pillage weapons.
佩勒指挥官 我知道你的人民
Commander Paylor. Your people,
和其他仍然在都城控制下的人一样 饱经苦难
have suffered more than just as anyone else in the hands of the Capitol.
这也是为什么我拒绝派我的部队继续进攻 那简直就是自杀
Which is why I won't condone a mass suicide.
如果我们不拿下2区 我们就无法进攻都城
If we don't take District 2, we won't get in to the Capitol.
我们能够使堡垒瘫痪
We'll be enough to disable the fortress,
因而不需要拿下它
instead of taking it.
你有什么计划
What do you have in mind?
我将它比作一个狼窝
We think of it like a wolf den.
我们没办法直接闯进去 现在我们有两个选择
You're not going to fight your way in, so you got two choices.
要么你把狼困在里面 要么你把它们逼出来
You trap the wolves inside or you flush them out.
我们没法直接攻进去
We can't attack straight on.
我们能不能派飞机对周围的山区进行轰炸
Couldn't we use a hovercraft to strike around it?
我们利用地形 我们知道山峰的弱点在哪
We use the mountains, we have weak spots and peaks.
利用一些地震方面的数据 我们设计一个炸弹
We could design the bomb to target some sequence season seismic data.
来引发山体滑坡
Trigger avalanches.
堵住所有的出口 切断他们的供应
Block all exits,cut off their supplies.
让他们的飞机无法起飞和降落
You make it impossible for them to launch their hovercrafts.
活埋他们
Bury them alive.
我们放弃对他们武器库的进攻计划
We forfeit any chance to control the weapons.
没错 我们这么做大大削弱都城的力量
Yes, but we'd place a weaken in Capitol.
但那里面还有平民
There're civilians in there.
我们应该留个投降的机会给他们
They should be given a chance to surrender.
保留一个补给隧道 以便他们的人撤出
Use one of the supply tunnels for the evacuees
这比12区的遭遇要好太多了
That's a luxury we weren't given when they fire- bombed 12.
肯定有更好的解决方法的
There's got to be a better way.
我提议我们制造山崩封住出口 但保留火车隧道畅通
I suggest we try the avalanche but leave the train tunnel alone.
平民可以跑到广场上
Civilians can escape into the square
我们的部队可以在那接受他们的投降
where our armies will be waiting for their surrender.
让所有的医疗人员在那边待命
We should have every available medic standing by.
如果他们不投降呢
And if they won't surrender?
那么我们需要一个有说服力的人来劝降
Then we will need a compelling voice to persuade them.
凯特尼斯 把敌人活埋或者用你的箭将敌人的飞机击落
What's the difference, Katniss.
这有什么区别呢
Crushing the enemy alive or blown them out of the sky with one of Beetee's arrows,
完全就是一码事
it's the same thing.
我们在8区被空袭了
We were under attack in District 8.
而且我们击落的飞机里没有平民
And that hovercraft wasn't filled with civilians.
那有什么关系呢
It doesn't matter.
哪怕那些平民只是拖拖地板 也是在帮敌人啊
You feel civilians are just mopping floors,they're helping the enemy.
我觉得干掉他们没什么问题
If they have to die,I can live with that.
支持都城的没一个好东西
No one who supports the Capitol is innocent.
你这种滥杀无辜的思想也好不到哪去
What about the kind of thinking you can kill whoever you want.
为了保持各区的秩序 你就把孩子送到饥饿游戏的赛场中去
You can send kids off to the Hunger games to keep the Districts in line.
凯特尼斯 这是战争
It's war, Katniss.
有时杀戮不是出于个人恩怨
Sometimes killing isn't personal.
而且谁又会知道是我们做的呢?只是你自己太偏执罢了
Figure if anyone who knew that it was you.
大家都明白 战争总是和个人私欲紧密相连
I, of all people know that it's always personal.
凯特尼斯 不用担心
Don't worry, Katniss.
会有幸存者的
There will be survivors.
现在想想你待会要说些什么
Let's focus on what it is you got to say.
- 普鲁塔克已经拟好了演讲稿 - 我不会念那份稿子的
- Now, Plutarch wrote a speech- I'm not saying that.
- 嗯 我也觉得你不会 只是
- Okay, I didn't think so.- Just
我只是提醒你 你的演讲会被直播
Just remember you're talking to everybody.
起义军、都城的人、幸存者和投降的人
And not just the rebels but the Capitol and the survivors into
都会看到你的演讲
well, to lay down their arms.
所以你的演讲要有足够的煽动性
So, you might want to experiment with a little sensitivity when you warn them.
演讲简练些 要让他们大吃一惊
Make it quick, the explosion.
我是凯特尼斯 艾佛丁
This is Katniss Everdeen,
我在2区的腹地向这些仍然忠于都城的人们发表讲话
speaking to all of the loyalist from the heart of District 2.
幸存者的乘坐的火车来了
Survivors.Inbound!
准备好
Ready! Ready!
所有人就位 架起枪
Arms at ready, guns up!
我们需要保护你撤下去
We got to get you back.
他们来了
Here they come!
所有人靠后站
Everybody, stand back!
冲上去
Everybody, go!
- 趴在地上  - 把他们赶下车来
- On the ground! - Get them off the train!
放下武器
Put your weapons down.
趴在地上
Get on the ground!
放下你们的武器 马上
Put your weapons down, now!
放下武器!
Weapons down.
你 放下武器
You, put it down.
放下..放下武器
Put itPut your weapons down!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
你 放下武器
You, drop it!
放下武器
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
- 别开枪  - 都别开枪
- Hold your fire.- Stop!
别开枪
Stop!
- 别开枪  - 都别开枪
- Hold your fire! - Stop!
- 别开枪
Hold your fire!
- 他需要治疗  - 别开枪
- He needs help! - Hold your fire!
放下武器
Drop it.
给我一个不开枪杀你的理由
Give me one reason I shouldn't shoot you.
放下武器
Drop the gun!
我不能
I can't.
我觉得这就是问题所在
I guess that's the problem, isn't it?
我们炸了你们的矿井
We blew up your mine.
你们把我们的家乡夷为平地
You burned my district to the ground.
我们每个人都有相互残杀的理由
We each have every reason to want to kill each other.
如果你杀了我
So, if you want to kill me too.
某个人会很开心
Make someone happy.
我已经厌倦和斯诺的棋子互相杀戮了
I'm tired of killing slaves for him.
我可不是他的棋子
I'm not a slave.
我是
I am.
那就是为什么我杀了加图
That's why I killed Cato
他杀了斯莱士
and he killed Thresh
斯莱士杀了克拉芙
and Thresh killed Clove.
总是这样不停的循环下去 最后你猜谁赢了
It just goes around and around and who wins?
当然 赢家总是斯诺
Always Snow.
我已经厌倦了成为他游戏里的棋子了
I'm done being a piece in his Game.
12区 2区 我们本来能和平共处
District 12, District 2 we have no fight.
战争是都城挑起的
Except the one the Capitol gave us.
为什么你要抵抗我们起义军呢
Why are you fighting the rebels?
为什么要与你的邻居兵戎相见呢?
Your neighbors?
为什么要与你的家人手足相残呢?
Your family?
这些人不是你们的敌人
These people are not your enemy!
我们只有一个敌人
We all have only one enemy.
那就是斯诺
And that's Snow.
他让我们每个人堕落腐化
He corrupts everyone and everything.
让我们这些本该和睦相处的人相互残杀
He turns the best of us against each other.
别再为他卖命了
Stop killing for him!
今晚 我们把枪口对准都城
Tonight, turn your weapons to the Capitol.
对准斯诺
Turn you weapons to Snow.
今晚 把你的枪口对准都城
Tonight, turn your weapons to the Capitol.
对准斯诺
Turn you weapons to Snow.
别开枪
Hold you fire!
干杯
A toast.
安东尼奥斯
Antonius.
我们最精锐的部队已经阵亡在那座山里了
With our best troops crushed in the mountains
就在我们谈话的时候 敌人还在向我们进军
and the rebels marching on us as we speak.
所以我想问问 我们到底在庆祝什么
What do we celebrate?
先生 我认为我们在庆祝嘲笑鸟之死
The death of the Mockingjay, Sir.
虽然皮塔没能杀了她 她的自大葬送了自己的性命
If Peeta didn't kill her her own arrogance did.
当然
Of course.
同样也是这么一种肤浅的思想 让你做出了
That's the same facile thinking that led you to divert
把我们最为精锐的部队派进2区这样一个错误的决定
our best peacekeepers into District 2.
你有一个坏习惯 喜欢在一切还未尘埃落定时就盖棺定论
You have the habit of burying people before they are dead.
如果嘲笑鸟真的死了
If the Mockingjay was gone,
叛军会利用她的烈士形象大肆宣传
the rebels would already be using her as a martyr.
安东尼奥斯首相 你说的不对
No, Minister Antonius.
我觉得我们不是在庆祝嘲笑鸟之死
I'm afraid that is not what we were toasting at all.
先生 你说的对
Yes, Sir.
我们的部队能抵抗住叛军
The rebels can be held off out
叛军几天后就会抵达
The rebels will reach the outskirts of the Capitol
都城的外围
in a matter of days.
我们把外围街区的军队撤下来
We'll evacuate the outer blocks
放叛军进来
to let them in.
把所有的防空导弹准备好
I want all anti- aircraft defenses ready,
保住制空权
so we're secured from the skies.
放他们进城
Lure them into the city
然后我们布下的陷阱会让他们每前进一步都得付出惨痛的代价
and then our gamemakers will make them pay for every inch with blood.
让所有的探头监控这一切
I want every camera watching.
我们要让他们的前进变成一种折磨
We will turn their advance into a celebration of suffering.
还要用摄像机录下他们死亡的过程 让我们的子孙后代有机会欣赏那些场景
Let each moment be captured for all posterity.
所以
So
安东尼奥斯首相 我们到底在庆祝什么呢
What do we toast tonight Minister Antonius?
我们在庆祝一个光辉的时代
We toast to the glorious era
终于可悲的结束了
coming to it's bitter end.
哈哈 找到你了
Well, there she is.
嘲笑鸟
The Mockingjay.
噢 看看我身上这些伤疤
Oh, that itch you gave.
天 我对我们打的那一架可是记忆犹新啊 现在回想起来还会浑身起鸡皮疙瘩
Oh, man, the feel. I mean I still have goose bumps.
你应该不会介意吧
You don't mind, do you?
他们没再给我注射吗啡了
They cut off my supply of morphine.
那个主治医生每天都来看我 尝试着
This head doctor that comes in and sees me everyday, she tried to
让我平静下来 让我适应这里的生活
help me adjust to reality like some
仿佛就像这个兔子窝里真的有人了解我一样
Like some guy from this rabbit warren actually knows anything about my reality.
每次开会时他都要重申好几遍：你是安全的
At least 20 times in a session he tells me that I'm totally safe.
你不会受到都城的迫害
Safe from the Capitol.
或是遭受斯诺的暴政
Safe from Snow.
嘲笑鸟 你怎么看 你真的有安全感吗
What about you, Mockingjay? You feeling totally safe?
在我中弹前 我都没感到安全过
Till I got shot.
天 那子弹根本没碰到你呢
Oh, please.The bullet didn't even touched you.
这些突发情况高层早就预料到了 你身上的“戏服”当然是防弹的了
Something they thought about.Of course your costume would be bulletproof.
所以你到底受了什么伤呢
So, what are your injuries?
肋骨和肺部受伤了
Bruised ribs.Bruised lung.
真奇怪 他们怎么不给你换个新的肺
I'm surprised they haven't found you a new lung.
我身上有两个肺呢 要不要从我身上拿一个?
Well, I got 2 do you want one of mine?
我的意思是 每个人都要保护你的生命安全
I mean, it's everybody's job to keep you alive.
这就是你讨厌我的原因吗
Is that why you hate me?
那只是部分原因
Partly.
你真的很虚伪
You're also a little hard to swallow.
你主演的那一幕幕闹剧和你那些帮助弱者的举动都显得那么低劣可笑
The whole tacky romance drama and the defender- of- the- helpless act.
虽说你帮助弱者时不像是在演戏
Even though it's not an act.
但这一切都让你显得更加令人讨厌
Which makes you even more unbearable.
能够亲口说出这些真是感到如释重负啊
Feel free to take any of this personally.
你应该去当嘲笑鸟 你想说什么就说什么
You should have been the Mockingjay nobody has to tell you what to say.
但没人看好我
But nobody likes me.
至少你还是自由的
You're free.
在这里是挺自由 但是在别的地方
Maybe here, but
都城里的人们只因为你而感到恐惧
In the Capitol, you're the only thing they're scared of.
那只是些我家人带来的小玩意儿
It's just stuff my family brought.
这是皮塔带来的?
This from Peeta?
没错
Yep.
都城的那帮人真是让我们不得安宁啊
They messed us up pretty good, didn't they?
我们给他看了些你在2区演讲的镜头
We showed him footage of your speech in 2.
他脑子里还是有对你的真实记忆的
He had real memories of you.
这不代表我可以去看他了啊
That still doesn't mean I am going in there.
他已经被捆住了 不会伤害你的
He's strapped down.He can't hurt you.
不 我不是那个意思
No, This is different.
海米奇 我真的不想见他
Haymitch, I really don't want to.
这不是你想不想的问题
Well, it doesn't matter what you want.
这都是为了皮塔好 试试没坏处的
It's for Peeta.What's the harm in trying.
我还以为你死了
I watched you die.
- 你看起来真糟糕 - 你看起来好多了
- You look terrible.- You looked better.
你说这话时一点也不真诚
You're not remotely nice to say that to me now.
我从来就不是个真诚的人 你才是
I was never the nice one you were.
当我看你倒下去的时候
When I saw you die,
我想起了一些事
I remembered something.
想起了那些面包
About the bread.
我想起那是个雨天
I remember you in the rain.
我故意把面包烤焦
And I burned it on purpose,
为了送面包给你吃
to give it to you.
我记得我妈妈还揍了我
I remember my mother hitting me.
因为我没把那些焦面包扔给猪
I was supposed to give it to the pig.
在那之前我好几天没吃东西了
That was the first I've eaten in days.
我怎么可能为了你去受那样一顿毒打
How I take a beating like that for you?
因为你很善良
Because you are kind
很大方
and generous.
- 人们都说你喜欢我 - 有人说我喜欢你?
- And people said you loved me.- Did people say you loved me?
这就是斯诺折磨你的原因
They said that's why Snow tortured you.
因为他想折磨我
To hurt me.
斯诺说你所说的一切都是假的
Snow says everything that comes out of your mouth is a lie.
我所知道的是要是当时我把那些面包扔给猪
All I know is that I would have saved myself a lot of suffering.
我就可以少受些折磨了
If I had just given that bread to the pig.
我只想衷心的对你道声谢
I think the only thing left to say is thank you.
我要去都城
I need to be in the Capitol.
不 你的任务已经完成了
No, you've done your job.
嘲笑鸟 你已经做的很好了 你成功的使所有区团结在一起
You've been very successful as the Mockingjay you've unified the Districts.
现在我们希望你好好休息
And now we want you to rest
保养好自己的身体
and to heal.
起义军最后一次看见我的时候 我还躺在地上
The last the rebels saw me I was lying on the ground.
凯特尼斯 你放心 我不会让我们之前的宣传付诸东流的
Katniss, we won't let this momentum go to waste.
我们就在13区 就在这里拍一些短片
We will shoot more propos right here in 13.
证明你还活着
Showing them that you're alive.
- 我应该和部队待在一块 - 这和你上前线效果是一样的
- I should be with the troops.- It will be like being on the front line.
就我们的官兵所知道的 你被一颗子弹击中心脏但却幸存下来
As far as the soldiers know you survived a bullet to the heart.
我觉得他们能明白为什么你没能和他们并肩作战
I think they will understand why you're not with them.
我们赢得这场战争之后 就用飞机送你过去 接受他们的投降
When we win this war we'll fly you in for the surrender.
受降典礼需要你出席 你对我们来说至关重要
We'll need you for the ceremony.You are very valuable to us.
你要我做什么都没问题
I'll do whatever you need me to do.
从今往后
From this day forward,
无论是生老病死
in sickness and in health,
还是富贵贫穷
for richer or poorer,
我都会好好的爱你 珍惜你
I promise to love and cherish you each day.
我 芬尼克 奥戴尔
I, Finnick Odair.
与安妮 克莱斯塔结为夫妻
Take you, Annie Cresta as my wife from this day forward,
一生一世
together or apart we will always be united.
永不分离
One life.
志同道合
One purpose.
长相厮守
One destiny.
现在你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
你去看望了皮塔吧
You saw Peeta, didn't you?
有没有替我向他问好
Would you tell him hi for me?
你知道他可是我的老朋友啦
We're old friends, you know.
我们在都城被关在同一间牢房里
We had a joint in the cells in the Capitol,
对彼此的尖叫声都十分熟悉呢
we're very familiar with each other's screams.
我要去杀了斯诺
I'm going to kill Snow.
只要他活着一天我们就一天不得安生
Nothing is good or safe while he's alive.
杀他之前我不想再演讲一番了
And I can't make another speech about it.
不想再对着镜头
No more cameras.
不想再拍宣传片
No more propos.
不想再演戏了
No more games.
当我杀他的时候 我要他看着我的眼睛
He needs to see my eyes when I kill him.
嘲笑鸟终于开始有主见啦
Now you're talking.
我在想有没有别的法子去都城
Find a way to the Capitol when everyone is looking the other way.
我刚刚听到有几个医务人员在聊天 他们今天半夜要把物资
I heard the medics talking, they're shipping supplies to the front line
送到前线去
from Hanger 2 around midnight, tonight.
我本打算从中偷点止痛药之类的药品 但我想了想
Medicines, painkillers I was going to steal something in mess hall but I guess I could
我可以留在这为你作掩护
just stay here and cover for you.
凯特尼斯 即使他是总统 你也能杀了他
Anybody can kill anybody, Katniss even the president.
只要你愿意牺牲自己
You just have to be willing to sacrifice yourself.
走之前上去跳支舞吧
Don't you want Snow to see you dance?
是她
It's her.
嗨
Hey.
- 我以为你还在医院里呢 - 之前是呆在那
- I thought you were in the hospital.- I was.
来吧
Come on.
她去那里干什么?
What is she doing?
那真是令人沮丧啊 她自己跑出去了
Well, it's so frustrating that she goes rogue.
她竟然敢违抗我的命令
This isn't just about a lesson it's insubordination.
让第一架回来的飞机把她送回来
Bring her on the first hovercraft back.
说什么呢 现在不能让她回来
Don't be ridiculous she can't come back now.
她现在就是个传奇
She's an epic.
在前线受了枪伤 却活了下来
In the front line surviving a gun shot wound
我都写不出一个比这更好的剧本了
I couldn't stage it better myself.
是啊
No.
让她待在前线吧
She's going to stay where she is.
她所做的一切
And whatever she's doing we conceived it.
都是在我们的计划掌控之中的
It was our plan all along.
当然
Of course it was.
海文斯比先生
Mr. Heavensbee.
你是制订规则的人
You are the gamemaker.
我要让所有人知道无论她采取什么行动
I want everyone to know whatever game she's playing.
她都是在为我们卖命
She's playing for us.
我是第八区的指挥官佩勒
I'm commander Paylor of District 8.
我和你们一样 都是在前线浴血奋战的士兵
I'm a soldier like all of you, so
我想说的是
Here's what I know.
这是我们一生中第一次看到13个区的人们在一起并肩作战
For the first time in our lifetimes we're standing together with 13 districts.
我认为我们已经创造了历史
From what I see here we already made history.
但我们不应该就此满足
But history didn't stop to celebrate.
我们正面对一个顽固不化 拒绝投降的敌人
And we are facing an enemy that will not change and will never surrender.
斯诺总统将部队撤下 加强了城中心的守卫
President Snow has pulled back peacemakers to fortify the center of the city.
他正从都城外围撤离居民
He's evacuating residents from the outer blocks.
平民们感到恐慌绝望
The civilians will be confused and desperate.
我命令你们不能伤害平民
You are under orders not to target them.
我们会部署医疗兵来帮助这些需要帮助的人
We are deploying medical brigades to help anyone in need.
我们要向都城人民证明我们是善良的
We'll show the Capitol people who we are.
为了迟缓我们的进攻 斯诺总统在城内布下了许多地雷
To slow our advance, President Snow is building a minefield of traps.
和一些被称作“豆荚”的杀人装置
And lethal devices called "Pods".
敌人发明这些残忍陷阱的目的是杀死我们的士兵 并从中取乐
The sadistic inventions the gamemakers meant to make sport of our deaths.
如果我们的部队能闯过城中的陷阱和守卫关卡
If our armies make it past peacekeepers and other defenses,
我们将包围斯诺的宅邸
we'll converge in the center of the city at Snow's mansion
到时我们将不仅仅是轰开他的大门
Where we won't just unlock his gates,
还解放了整个帕纳姆
but unshackle all of Panem.
如果我们不幸阵亡
If we die
希望我们死的值得
Let it be for a cause and not a spectacle.
如果我们活下来了 愿上天保佑我们帕纳姆
If we succeed, let it be for all of Panem and let it be forever.
是的 你们已经创造了历史
Yes, you already made history.
历史
But the future
将在明天拂晓我们的总攻中
Our future starts tomorrow at dawn.
掀开新的篇章
When we march together into the Capitol.
你将加入451小队?
Squad 451?
看起来你已经准备好你的食物了
Looks like you got your meals covered.
- 我希望在走之前准备周全 - 别瞒着我了
- I'm trying to be prepared.- Don't lie to me.
我们这辈子都在一起打猎
We've been hunting together all our lives.
我知道你这次想离开小队单独行动
I know when you're going to go off on your own.
你这次还打算把我扔下吗?
You're going to leave me behind too?
作为你的部下
As you fellow soldier,
我建议你还是和你的分队待在一起吧
I suggest that you stay with your unit.
如果你一定要来 我也没法阻止你
I couldn't stop you if you wanted to come.
霍桑 艾佛丁
Hawthorne.Everdeen.
来见见大家
Come meet your new unit.
我是杰克逊中尉
I'm Lieutenant Jackson.
现在我向你介绍一下与你同行的小队成员
And I want to introduce you to your squad.
这是米歇尔少尉 帕纳姆的神枪手
This is the second lieutenant Mitchell.The best sharp shooter in Panem.
这两位 列格姐妹 来自第一战斗师
These are the Leeg sisters First Combat Division.
这位是霍姆斯下士
And this is Corporal Homes.
芬尼克?
Finnick?
- 你和我们一起去吗? - 没错
- Are you with us? - Looks like it.
蜜月期真短啊
That's a short honeymoon.
是啊
Yeah.Well...
我想在我们拿下都城后
I guess we got to have one in the Capitol.
- 我们会在那再度一次蜜月 - 集合
- After we take it.- Gather around.
451中队
Squadron 451.
我是你们的总指挥
You’re my unit.
杰克逊中尉是副指挥
Lieutenant Jackson is my second in command.
你们中的每一个人都是战场上的精英
Each one of you is elite in some form of combat.
但我们不是战斗部队
But we are a non- combat unit,
所以我们将跟在前线部队后面
so, we'll be following days behind the front line troops.
作为明星小队
You are to be the onscreen faces of the invasion.
你们的行动将被直播
The Star squad.
指挥部认为直播你们的行动能鼓舞军心
It's been decided that you are most effective when seen by the masses.
所以我们不参加战斗?
So, we're not going to fight?
士兵 我命令你做什么你就做什么
You do whatever you are ordered to do, soldier.
现在轮不到你提问
It's not your job to ask question.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
我们接到的指示是在进军都城时
Our instructions are to shoot propaganda footage
拍摄宣传镜头
on the battle scars troop to the Capitol.
你们每个人都是被精心挑选出来 去震慑敌人
You are handpicked to intimidate their forces.
劝诫他们投降
And inspire surrenders.
即使我们大多数时间都在离前线数英里的地方拍摄
Even though we'll be working on abandon streets miles behind the front line,
我向你们担保 无论他把我们派到哪里 都不会绝对的安全
I guarantee you, wherever they put us it will not be safe.
我们将身处战场
This is a war zone.
我们可能遇到活动的“豆荚”和敌人的部队
It is likely that we'll encounter both active Pods and peacekeepers.
你们是都城的重点抓捕目标
You're considered high value targets to the Capitol.
要是不幸落入敌手 用这种"夜锁"药丸自杀
In the event of capture you'll be given a nightlock pill.
服用后毒性立马发作 杰克逊中尉请将药丸分发下去
A poison that acts immediately.Lieutenant Jackson do the honors.
我向你们简要介绍下“豆荚”
I've already briefed you on the Pods.
仔细听好了 每个街区上都有这种陷阱
I remind you they are on every block.
上级给我们小队分配了一个“全息图”装置
Our unit has been given a HOLO.
这是一个数据库 内置都城的详细地图
A database that contain the detailed map of the Capitol
上面记录了每一个已知“豆荚”的具体位置
and the list of every known Pod.
这些陷阱
These Pods,
能被例如炸弹和一些不幸靠近的倒霉蛋触发
can trigger anything from bombs to traps, to mutts.
没有这个装置我们就无法行动
We cannot move without this device.
同时这个数据库可能是不完整的
There's no guarantee that our database is complete.
也可能有我们尚未注意到的“豆荚”
There can be new Pods that we are not aware of.
我们不想让敌人知道我们有这么清楚的情报
Because we don't want the gamemakers to know we have this Intel.
因此装置内部有一个自毁装置 你启动这个开关
There's a self- destruct on it You flip this switch.
说三声"夜锁",它就会自爆 爆炸半径10英寸
You say, "nightlock" 3 times it's going to blow itself and anything within a 10 foot radius.
不要擅自行动
Stay within our unit.
即便我们有这个装置 敌人也可能布下新的"豆荚"
Even with the HOLO, it's likely that new Pods have been set.
不管那里面是什么 那肯定能要了你的命
Whatever they contain they are meant to kill you.
先生们女士们
Ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到第76届饥饿游戏
Welcome to the 76th Hunger Games.
我从未见过这里空无一人
I've never seen this place so empty.
大家留心观察周围情况
Just keep your eyes open.
这附近有个陷阱
We got a Pod..
快找隐蔽物
Stay cover.
从这两栋楼中间射一箭
Shoot through those 2 buildings.
陷阱
Pod.
就在那 克雷西达
Right here.Cressida.
位置不错
Good.
凯特尼斯 准备好了就射击
When you're ready, Katniss.
停
Hold it.Pod is tighter.
开弓吧
Okay.
警报解除
All clear.
我觉得我们走不过这片雷区的
I don't think we can get across this minefield.
没有“全息图”就没法过雷区
Not without that HOLO.
指挥官醒着时我们没法拿走那个装置
We're not getting to get it off him while he's awake
记得校正我们俩的手表 今晚统一行动
Make sure we're on the same watch tonight.
那是政府军的卡车吗
Is that peacemakers?
451小队呼叫基地 一辆卡车从南面驶向我们的驻地 完毕
451 to Base. We got a truck coming in from the south, over.
小队明白 完毕
Copy that, over.
不必紧张 那是自己人
Stand down everyone, it's friendly.
我来自12区
I'm with District 12.
停下
Okay, stop.
住手 大家都冷静
Hold up.Everyone relax.
我们拿他怎么办
What are we doing?
杰克逊 铐上他
Jackson, cuff him.
士兵 这只是保险措施 弄清楚情况后我们会给你解开的
Soldier, this is just a precaution, until we have everything straighten out, yeah.
我来自12区
I'm District 12.
上级希望我们将他拍进宣传片
They want us to add him to the propo.
以证明他现在已经站到我们这边了
To show he's on our side now.
我们往前走几个街区 再给他拍一个短片
We'll move forward a few blocks tomorrow and shoot him a footage.
他甚至都不能控制住自己
He's not in control of himself.
现在我安排一个值班表 轮流看守他
I say we schedule an around the clock watch on him.
到17点 由列格姐妹俩负责
The Leegs till 1700.
17点到晚上19点 由赫姆斯和米歇尔负责
Homes and Mitchell till 1900.
把我也安排进值班表
Give me a watch.
到了关键时刻 你确定你能朝他开枪吗
If it ever came down to it you think you can shoot him?
那时我不是朝皮塔开枪 而是朝一个都城来的杂种开枪
I wouldn't be shooting Peeta.I'd be killing a Capitol mutt.
你这样说更让我不放心了
I'm not sure that kind of comment recommends you for the job either, soldier.
把她排进值班表
Put her in the rotation.
他肯定会试图杀了我
He's going to try to kill me.
尤其是当我们行动的时候 我肯定会激怒他
Especially with all this going on.It's going to set him off.
我们会牢牢看住他的
We'll keep him contained.
为什么科因这么做
Why would Coin do this?
我所知道的有限
Here's all I know.
那次在竞技场里她想救出来的是皮塔而不是你
It was Peeta that she wanted rescued from the arena.
她一点都不喜欢你
She never liked you.
她不喜欢那些她控制不住的人
She doesn't like anybody or anything she can't control.
- 所以她就让我置身于危险的境地? - 她说她不是故意为之 但实际上- So, she would put my life in danger?
- She denied, but...
怎么了?
What?
总有一天这场战争要结束
One way or another this war is going to come to an end.
他们承诺将会举行一场自由的选举
They promised a free election.
也许她已经将你视作一个威胁
Maybe she's starting to see you as a threat.
没人会支持我做领导人的
Nobody would think that I'd be a leader.
但如果要你支持某位候选人 你会选她吗
But you'll throw support to someone would it be her?
如果你不是毫不犹豫的回答道“会” 那么你对她来说就是个威胁
If your immediate answer isn't yes then you are dangerous.
她已经不需要你拍摄那些宣传片了 因为这些宣传片没有你一样也能拍下去
She doesn't need you as a rallying cry any more than these propos can be done without you.
你现在所做的一切只会让起义的势头继续高涨
Only one thing you could do now to add more fire to this rebellion.
死
Die.
凯特尼斯 我是不会让这种事情发生的
That's not going to happen under my watch, Katniss.
我会好好保护你的
I'm planning for you to have a long life.
为什么?你为什么要这么做?
Why? You don't owe me anything.
因为你付出了太多 理应享受胜利
Because you've earned it.
你知道吗 我们以前一起到过这儿的
We've been here before, you know?
什么?
What?
你脸上的表情
That look.
你这表情我以前看到过
I've seen that look.
那时你在决定你到底要不要杀了我
You're trying to decide whether or not you should kill me.
我从来没想过要杀了你
I never wanted to kill you.
我心里想的不是这个
That's not what I'm doing.
我们第一次在饥饿游戏上见面时
I saw with my own eyes.
我亲眼所见
In the first games
那次 我以为你要和卡瑞尔一起杀掉我
In the first games, I thought you were trying to help the Careers to kill me.
在那之后 我把你
After that, I saw you...
当成我的伙伴
as an ally.
朋友
Friend.
爱人
Lover
胜利者
Victor.
未婚妻
Fiancee.
敌人
Enemy
攻击目标
Target.
杂种 现在又多了个词：“伙伴”
Mutt.And now ally?
我已经彻底没法分清你到底是谁了
Yeah. I'll add it to the list of words I use to try to figure you out.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是没法分清事实的真假了
I just can't tell what's real and what's made up anymore.
那就多开口问问大家 安妮也是这么做的
Then ask.That's what Annie does.
问谁呢
Ask who?
问我们 我们是你的新同伴
Us.We're your new unit now.
你最喜欢的颜色是绿色
Your favorite color is green.
这个是真的吗
Is that's real?
是的 是绿色
Yeah.It's green.
你最喜欢的颜色是橙色
Yours is orange.
不..应该是亮橙色
Not...bright orange.
像日落一样温暖的亮橙色
Soft like the sunset.
谢谢
Thank you.
你曾是个画家
You're a painter.
是个面包师
You're a baker.
你总喜欢开着窗户睡觉
You always sleep with the windows open.
你喝茶时从不加糖
You never take sugar in your tea.
你系鞋带总是打双结
You always double- knot your shoelaces.
你说得对
You were right.
我不能走
I can't do this.
我觉得我们走不掉了
I guess we're not leaving anymore.
拿不到全息仪我们哪都去不了
We're not going anywhere without that HOLO.
各位听好了
Listen up.
这个弹夹是空的
The mag's empty.
为了他拍宣传片而准备的
It's for someone for the propo.
我们继续前进 向北走五个街区
Let's move.We're heading 5 blocks north.
都城里的平民们 我们不会伤害你们
To the Citizens in the Capitol.Our war is not with you.
战争结束后 你们也享有平等的民主权利
You will be a vital part of the democracy that follows our victory.
Be a vital part of the democracy that follows our victory.
- 记住了吗 - 记住了
- You got it.- Okay.
博格斯
Boggs.
这个拍摄点不错
This is a good spot.
- 走到那 到那个广场上去 - 好 让我们先探测一下周围
- Through there, in the courtyard.- Okay, let us clear it.
发现了一个陷阱
Got a Pod.
分散隐蔽
Split.Take cover
别靠近
Stay back.
警报解除 盖尔 赫姆斯跟着我
All clear.Gale, Homes, with me.
列格姐妹 注意两翼的动向
Leegs, take the wings.
艾佛丁 别动
Everdeen, no!
- 博格斯  - 所有人站在原地
- Boggs! - Hold your position.
- 博格斯
Boggs!
没事的 冷静
It's okay.
保护好“全息图”
The HOLO.The HOLO.
我已不适合指挥
Unfit for command.
移交指挥权
Transfer prime security clearance.
- 说出你的名字 - 凯特尼斯 艾佛丁
- Say your name.- Katniss Everdeen.
- 你为什么这么做? - 凯特尼斯
- What did you just do? - Katniss.
不要信任他们
Don't trust them.
必要时杀了皮塔
Kill Peeta if you have to.
别忘了你来这的目的
Do what you came to do.
博格斯你醒醒
Boggs?
醒醒啊
Come on.Come on.
他牺牲了
He's gone.He's gone.
大家快跑
Go! Go! Go! Now! Now!
- 走这边 - 不要停
- This way.- Keep moving!
凯特尼斯快跑
Katniss, go! Come on!
快跑到高处
Get to higher ground.Now!
芬尼克
Finnick!
皮塔
Peeta!
- 快走啊  - 我的天啊
- Let's go! - Oh God!
快跑
Come on.Come on.
快跑 不要停
Come on.Don't stop, let's go!
快走快走
Come on! Come on! We got to move!
快进去
Get inside.
大家都赶紧进去 快
Everybody inside! Go!
快
Go!
- 跟上  - 快走
- Hurry up! - Move!
- 快跑
- Go! Go! - Move!
不要停
Keep moving.
快跑到顶楼
Keep moving to the top.
跑上去
Go!
嘿 我抓住你了 嘘嘘嘘
Hey. Hey.I got you. Shh...
水位上涨的速度降低了
It's slowing down.
我们的性命仍然在他们的掌控中
Gamemakers are still running on the show.
- 451小队呼叫基地 完毕 - 各位 我们最好马上转移了
- 451 to Base, over.- Hey, we better move.
之前政府军不知道我们的方位 现在他们知道了
The peacemakers didn't know where we were, they do now.
那些监控探头发现了我们
Those surveillance cameras caught us.
451小队呼叫基地 请回答
451 to Base, come in.
此地不宜久待 我们必须马上走
This is a bad spot.We need to move, now.
451小队呼叫基地 完毕
451 to Base, over.
这没信号
I can't get a signal.
我知道回基地的路线 艾佛丁 把“全息图”给我
But I can get us back to Base.Everdeen, give me the HOLO
艾佛丁 我重复一遍 快给我 我们要行动了
Everdeen, what'd I just say? The HOLO, come on, let's go.
博格斯把它给了我
Boggs gave it to me.
- 你都在说些什么 - 博格斯确实这么做了
- What are you talking about? - He did.
他将指挥权移交给了她
He transferred security clearance to her.
我亲眼所见
I saw him.
他为什么这么做?
And why did he do that?
科因总统给了我一个特殊任务
I'm on special orders from Coin.
什么任务?
To do what?
暗杀斯诺总统
To assassinate President Snow.
我不信 不用多想就知道你在撒谎
I don't believe that for one second.
作为小队的新指挥官
As your new unit commander,
我命令你现在就将安全许可移交给我
I order you to transfer security clearance to me. Now
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
让我们暂且先别窝里斗
Let's not lose our heads here.
我不是在请求你 我命令你 把“全息图”给我
I'm not asking it again, Everdeen.Give me that HOLO.
她说的是事实 普鲁塔克想要我们把暗杀斯诺总统的过程直播出来
She's telling the truth.Plutarch wants it televised.
他认为如果我们能拍下那一幕
He thinks if we can film the Mockingjay assassinating Snow,
都城能更快的投降 避免更大的伤亡
It will make the Capitol surrender before the casualties get too high.
正当我们争执不休之时 大量政府军正朝这逼近
While we're arguing, there's a hundred peacekeepers on their way here.
博格斯说过你是和我们一伙的
Boggs promised me that when the time came you would help me.
好吧 士兵
Alright, soldier.
“全息图”是你的了
The HOLO is yours.
我觉得我们应该不会再被发现了 我们应该马上行动了
I don't think we're going to leave any footprints. We should move, now.
外面的大部分监控镜头都被油污遮住了
Most cameras outside should be covered up by the oil.
她的腿伤得太重 不能继续前进了
She can't move forward like this.Her leg's too bad.
我们需要带她撤离
We have to evacuate her.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我会和她待在一起
I'll stay with her.
我承诺我们一与指挥部联系上
As soon as we make contact,
我们就让他们派人来找你们
we will send somebody back.I promise you.
各位 我们出发
Alright, everybody, move out.
- 拉上他一起走 - 行动
- Let's get him up.- Go.
你能自己走吗?
Can you walk?
走这边
Come on this way.
拉上那些窗帘
Get these curtains closed.
列格姐妹俩在劫难逃
It's the Leegs.
强制观看 所有帕纳姆国居民注意
下午好 我是凯萨·富莱克曼
Good afternoon I'm Caesar Flickerman.
下面继续播报都城保卫战的最新战况
Hear about continuing coverage of the defense of the Capitol.
今天 我们的部队正顽强抵抗着叛军的进攻
Today, as our peacekeepers valiantly hold off the rebels,
我要告诉大家一个好消息
our story takes a surprising twist.
凯特尼斯 艾佛丁 我们曾经的骄傲
Katniss Everdeen.Our once favourite daughter,
与一些曾经的胜利者们渗透进城市内部
has infiltrated the city with some of the Victors.
他们的名字大家都很熟悉了
Who's names are all too familiar.
芬尼克 奥戴尔和皮塔 梅尔拉克
Finnick Odair and Peeta Mellark.
很明显 没有永恒的盟友
Clearly, some alliances don't last forever.
各位观众看一看几分钟前发生的一幕
Take a look at what happened just a moment ago.
当我们的部队包围了凯特尼斯 艾佛丁
When our peacekeepers cornered Katniss Everdeen
和她那一队愚蠢的同伙时
and her band of foolish rebels.
无论是怎样一种自大的想法驱使她回到这里
Whatever arrogance brought this treacherous girl back to us.
你们马上就要目睹我们胜利的一幕 不仅对都城而言
You're about to witness a great victory, not only to the Capitol,
而是对所有帕纳姆而言
but for Panem.
好的 你们已经看到了
So, there you have it.
凯特尼斯 艾佛丁 燃烧的女孩
Katniss Everdeen, the girl on fire.
她曾经引发了一场场暴动
The girl who inspired so much violence.
到头来终究惨死
Seems to have met a violent end herself.
请继续关注我们的最新报道 我是凯萨·富莱克曼 感谢您的收看
Stay tuned for more information.Caesar Flickerman, thank you.
现在他们以为我们死了 我们下一步怎么办
So, now that we are dead what are we going to do?
这还不清楚吗?
Isn't it obvious?
下一步你们会干掉我
The next move is to kill me.
我害死了我的同伴
I murdered one of our squad members.
凯特尼斯说的对
Katniss is right.
我就是个杂种
I'm a mutt.
我下一次发作只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time before I snapped again.
我无法控制自己
I'm not in control.
给我一粒"夜锁"药丸
I need a nightlock pill.
这样我就能自杀了
So, I can die when I need to.
要是到了紧要关头 我会亲手杀了你
When it gets to that point I'll kill you myself.
我真是难以理解都城的上层都在想些什么
I don't think I ever really understood the Capitol until now.
克雷西达 都城
CRESSIDA CAPITOL
卡斯托 都城
CASTOR CAPITOL
波乐克斯 都城
POLLUX CAPITOL
梅萨拉 都城
MESSALLA CAPITOL
芬尼克 奥戴尔 4区
FINNICK ODAIR DISTRICT 4
皮塔 梅拉尔克 12区
PEETA MELLARK DISTRICT 12
凯特尼斯 艾佛丁 12区
KATNISS EVERDEEN DISTRICT 12
大家也都看到了  凯特尼斯 艾佛丁
So, Katniss Everdeen.
不过只是一个擅长箭术 反复无常的小丫头
A poor unstable girl was nothing but a small talent with a bow and arrow,
她死了
is dead.
她不聪明 也不配当领袖
Not a thinker.Not a leader.
不过是一群贱民拉出来册封的勇士罢了
Simply a face plucked for the masses.
她有用么 对于你们这伙人的革命当然有用
Was she valuable? She was extremely valuable to your rebellion.
因为你们毫无眼光 无法推选出一位优秀的领袖
Because you have no vision no true leader among you.
你们将自己称作起义军
You call themselves an alliance,
但我认为你们只不过是一群乌合之众罢了
but we saw what that means.
你们部队内斗不断 士兵之间斗的你死我活
Your soldiers are at each other's throats.
你们趁早安息去吧 帕纳姆人
Good night. Panem
要是还有人不认识我
For those of you who don't know me,
那我就自我介绍一下
please allow me to introduce myself.
我是总统科因
I am President Alma Coin,
起义军的领袖
leader of the rebellion.
我之所以打断你们总统的广播
I interrupted a broadcast from your president
是因为他正试图抹黑一位年轻、勇敢的姑娘
in which he attempted to defame a brave young woman.
一群贱民拉出来册封的勇士  他是这么称呼她的
A face, picked for the masses he called her.
册封  她可用不着
- Plucked.- As if a leader...
一位真正的领导  不用任何人册封
A true leader could be anything else.
我很荣幸能认识
I had the privilege of knowing
这位来自十二区的姑娘
a small town girl from the scene in District 12,
她撑过了饥饿游戏和世纪争霸赛
who survived the Hunger Games and the Quarter Quell.
她把一群奴隶变成一支具有强大战斗力的军队
And rose up and turn a nation of slaves into an army.
不管她是死是活 凯特尼斯永远是我们革命中不可替代的角色
Dead or alive. Katniss Everdeen will remain the face of this revolution.
就算她死了  她也绝不是白死
She will not have died for nothing.
我从来都没想到她把我看这么重
I have no idea I meant so much to her.
我们会替她完成她的遗愿 同时也是我们的目标 解放帕纳姆
Her vision and ours will be realised.
我们要建设一个自由的新帕纳姆国
A free Panem.
我们要民主
With self- determination for all.
我们会消灭一切妄图迫害帕纳姆人民
And in her memory, we will all find strength to rid Panem
的压迫者
of it's oppressors
保卫我们的国家
and be safe.
永远铭记嘲笑鸟
REMEMBER THE MOCKINGJAY
斯诺在他的宅邸里  他的宅邸在哪?
- Snow is in his mansion.- Where is that?
我们在这儿
That's us.
这是市中心
That's the city circle.
隔着大约70到75个街道
It's at least 70, 75 blocks north.
- 75个? - 是的
- 75 blocks? - Uh huh.
没人知道我们还活着  我们能好好利用这个有利条件
Nobody knows we're alive.This is our chance.
这几栋楼  从那里看得见斯诺的花园么
These buildings, do these look over Snow's garden?
我  可以的
- I...- They do.
只要他走出来  我就能一箭射死他
If he goes outside at all I can get a clear shot.
先别想那么远
We are getting ahead of ourselves here.
不管他们还在不在找我们  我们被困在这儿了
Whether they're looking for us or not, we're pinned down.
按那个按钮  把所有的"豆荚"搜出来
Hit that button scan for Pods.
走十步路就能撞见一个
Just about every 10 steps.
而且新布下的陷阱的这儿还没显示
Yeah, that doesn't even show the new ones.
所以到了街上我们将寸步难行
So, we can't go anywhere in the streets.
这红点还真是密集啊
And the red tops suggest to that.
我们也许能找到别的路
There might be another way.
我的兄弟对这些通道了如指掌
My brother knows these tunnels really well.
他原来在这儿的地下排污系统工作
He works sanitation down here.
后来他们割掉了他的舌头 真庆幸还留了他一条小命
I'm glad they made him an Avox.
嘿 波乐克斯
Hey. Hey.
你还好吗? 看着我
You're going to be okay? Look at me.
看着我
Look at me.
我们一定能安全穿过这里的  我保证
I promise.
我们花了5年时间才把他赎出来
It take us 5 years to buy his way out of here.
他才得以重见天日
He didn't see the sun once.
我们在这很容易被发现
We're too expose here.
先生 需要为您叫医生过来吗?
Shall I call you a doctor?
- 你说什么?- 需要为您叫医生过来吗?
- What did you say? - Shall I call your a doctor?
我以为你叫醒我是因为有比一个老年人的健康状况
I hope you waking me for something more urgent than
更为紧急的事
an old man's health.
他们没死 不知道怎么回事
I don't know how.
我们在监控里发现了他们的踪迹
We picked them up on a surveillance cam.
让我看看 我..我需要亲自确认
I- I need to see for myself.
是她 确实是她
It is her.
原来他们把战场转移到了地下
Her arena has moved underground.
看起来安全
Looks clear.
大家都没事吧?
Everybody, okay?
没事
Yeah.
好了 大家在这里先停会
Alright, everybody.Let's stop here for a bit
休息一下
and get some rest, yeah?
我放第一班哨
I'll take first watch.
皮塔 走过去
just step in there.
好了 大家都坐下休息吧
Alright, settle in, everybody.
凯特尼斯 轮到你放哨了
Katniss, your watch.
你应该知道 他们在我身上下了毒药
You know, the capital, they used tracker jacker venom on me.
13区的医生告诉我的 你也被叮过
You were stung once too.
我说的是真的吗?
Real or not real?
是
Real.
他们对我下毒后 会给我看我以前的照片
When they used the venom on me,they would show me pictures of my life.
但是有些不是真实的 是他们篡改过了的
They changed them.
一开始我分不清哪些是真实的
At first, they all- they all blend together, but now...
现在我能分辨出一些了
now I can sort them out a little.
像是...被他们改过的一小部分 有一些
Like the...little ones that they changed,they have this...
有一些重声 就像是
this choir it's like they're
他们闪着光 是被修饰过了的
They are shiny,they've been glossed over.
你该好好休息下
You should get some rest.
你仍在努力保护我 我说的对吗?
You're still trying to protect me, real or not real?
对
Real.
我们都会这么做
That's what you and I do.
让对方活着
Keep each other alive.
凯特尼斯
Katniss.
那是什么声音?
What is that?
我们该走了 我们必须马上离开这里
We got to go.We got to get out of here now.
那是蜥蜴人 他们放出了蜥蜴人
Mutts.They release mutts.
波力克斯 最快出去的路在哪儿?
Pollux, what's is the fastest way out?
快点 起来 快走
Come on, wake up.Go!
快跑 快跑 快跑 快点 快点
- Move! Move! Move! Move! - Come on! Come on! Come on!
波力克斯 快带我们出去
Pollux, lead us out of here!
快点
Come on.
杰克逊
Jackson!
卡斯托
Castor!
全体后退
Fall back!
快走
Move.
凯特妮斯 快走 快点
Katniss. come on! Move!
凯特妮斯
Katniss.
走 快..快走
GO! Go, go, go...!
走 走 快走
Go, go, go!
凯特妮斯
Katniss!
芬尼克
Finnick!
- 凯特妮斯 - 夜锁模式
- KATNISS ! - Nightlock.
夜锁模式
Nightlock.
快走快走快走 快点
Come on. Come on! Come on. Come on!
快走 别停下来!别停下来
Let's go! Keep moving! Keep moving!
走 走
Go! Go!
快走 别停
Keep going.Keep going!
皮塔 快点
Peeta, come on.
皮塔
Peeta!
皮塔 我们得赶紧走 我是个怪物
- Peeta, we have to get going! - I'm a mutt!
我们得快走 我不行了
- I can't hang on.
你可以 走开 我是个怪物
- Leave me. I'm a mutt!
看着我 看着我
Look at me! Look at me.
别离开我
Stay with me.
永远不
Always.
快走
Come on.
我知道我们在哪
I know where we are.
我知道一个地方 在这楼上
I know a place.Up those stairs.
快 快点
Keep going.
通缉
盖尔 霍桑
皮塔 梅拉尔克
有人来了
Someone's coming.
关门 关上门
Shut the door.Shut the door.
不不不 她是好人 没事的
It's okay.
没事的
底格里斯 还记得我吗? 我是和普鲁塔克一伙的
Tigris, you remember me? I'm with Plutarch's Underground.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
安全
Clear!
我认识你
I know you.
你是饥饿游戏的造型师
You're a stylist in the Games.
要不是斯诺 我也不会变成这副模样
Until Snow decided I wasn't pretty enough anymore.
我是来杀他的
I'm here to kill him.
他需要缝合伤口
He's got to need stitches.
我撒谎了
I made it up.
都是我编的
All of it.
科因没有分配什么特别任务
There is no special mission from Coin.
那只是我个人的计划而已
It's only my plan.
我害死了那么多同伴
Everyone that's dead,is dead because of me. I...
因为我说了假话
I lied
我们知道  我们早就知道这些了
We know.We all knew.
那些来自十三区的士兵们
- Soldiers from 13 didn't...- Do you...
你真以为杰克逊相信你身负科因的命令吗
Do you really believe that Jackson thought you had orders from Coin?
她只信任博格斯  所以她想让你接着完成他的使命
She trusted Boggs, so he clearly wanted you to go on.
我没想到事情会成这样
I never meant for this to happen.
我辜负了他们
I failed them.
是我害死了他们  我害死了了芬尼克
I killed- I killed them.I killed Finnick.
我很抱歉  波乐克斯
I'm sorry, Pollux.
真的很对不起他们
So sorry.
葛利姆
Glimmer.
马弗
Marvel.
玛格斯
Mags.
克拉芙
Clove.
瓦尔里斯
Wiress.
芸香
Rue.
他们的死换来了什么
What do all those deaths mean?
他们的死意味着我们的生死由不得自己控制
They mean that our lives were never ours.
我们算不上活着 因为我们连选择的余地都没有
There was no real life because we didn't have any choice.
我们的生死 斯诺说了算
Our lives, belong to Snow and our deaths do too.
但是 如果你杀了他 凯特尼斯
But if you kill him, Katniss.
如果你终结了这一切
If you end all of this...
我们的朋友就没有白死
All those deaths they mean something.
辛纳
Salla.
博格斯
Boggs.
卡斯托
Castor.
杰克逊. 芬尼克
Jackson.Finnick.
他们就死而无憾
They chose this.
他们选择追随你的脚步
They chose you.
伤口要保持干净  防止伤口感染
You should keep this clean otherwise it will get infected.
你应该把我拷起来
You should cuff me.
跟我待在一起不安全
It's not safe with me yet.
我到过这里
I have moments when I'm here...
我想起了更多的事
My memories are getting better but...
但有些时候 我就像在梦游
Other times, it's like I'm sleepwalking.
你真该把我拷起来
You should cuff me.
谢谢你的水
Thanks, for the water.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
嗯 我一连好几天都睡不着
Yeah, I haven't slept in days either.
第一次饥饿游戏的时候  我真该自愿把你换下来的
I should have volunteered to take your place in the first Games.
那么要是你那么做了
Well, you couldn't.
那她会永远记恨你
And she- she'd never have forgiven you.
她希望你照顾好她的家人 而你也的确这么做了
She wanted you to be there and take care of her family and you did.
她不能失去你
She can't lose you.
她真的爱你
She really loves you.
你看她在世纪争霸赛亲吻你的样子
The way she kissed you in the Quarter Quell.
她可从来没那么亲过我
She never kissed me like that.
盖尔 你知道那只是逢场作戏而已
You know it's part of the show, Gale.
不 是你赢得了她的心
No, you won her over.
你为她放弃了一切
You gave up everything for her.
这不是个大问题
It's not going to be an issue much longer.
不知道我们三个人能否一起平安的完成这个任务
I doubt all 3 of us are going to make it out of this.
若是我们都活下来了
And if we do, then...
选谁就由她自己决定 对吧
It's her problem who to choose, right?
是啊
Yeah.
但是呢  我总觉得她谁都选不出来
Well, I do know that Katniss will pick whoever she can't survive without.
机动防爆盾  不是我们的
Mortar shells.It's not ours.
政府军一定是用它们把起义军挡在城市外头了
Peacekeepers must shelling the rebels outside the city.
算不上是城市外头
That's not outside the city.
太阳出来了
Sun's coming up.
我听到一些微弱的枪声  可能是佩勒或者是莱姆的部队攻过来了
There's some small arms fire.Could be Paylor maybe Lyme.
起义军已经逼近了
The rebels are close.
就是这儿了
This is it.
强制观看 所有帕纳姆国居民注意
告知距离市中心半英里之外的市民
To all Capitol citizens more than half a mile outside the city circle.
现在要强制疏散
I'm announcing a mandatory evacuation.
都到我的宅邸这边来  我给你们提供避难所
Come to the mansion.I'm promising you shelter and sanctuary.
所有的难民  到我的家里来
All refugees, come to my home
我们提供食物
There, you will be provided with food,
药品  还保证你们孩子的安全
medicine, safety for your children.
我保证誓死保护你们
And you will have my solemn oath to protect you until my dying breath.
你们应该快点赶上这末班车
You should hurry up with that last part.
我们的敌人可一点都不如我们
Our enemies are not like us.They do not share our values.
他们提供不了我们的庇护
They have never known our comfort and our sophistication.
他们还鄙视我们提供的庇护  你们千万不要搞错
And they despise us for it.Make no mistake.
他们不是来解放我们的
They are not coming to liberate us.
他们是来摧毁我们的生活
They are coming to destroy our way of life.
他们会埋葬我们
They are coming to bury us.
他现在还在大楼里吗
Is he still in the mansion?
皮塔
Peeta?
是的  我认得这房间
Yeah.I recognize the room.
在哪儿
Where's that?
隔着五个街道
About 5 blocks away.
我们就在这里  不是在主干道上
We are right here off the avenues.
大楼就在这里  岗楼呢
- The mansion is here - What about the Pods?
他们有可能会关掉这边的岗楼  以增援受攻击的地方
Well, they'd probably deactivate the Pods around here for the resident safety.
能行的
That could work.
我能再靠近一些
I can get close enough.
每一个治安官都会待命
Every peacekeeper is going to be waiting.
随时准备干掉我们几个
Next to our faces on every billboard.
斯诺提供给难民的避难所
Snow's offering shelter to all the refugees.
就在北面
Head straight north.
难民肯定成千上万
There's going to be thousands of refugees,
我们混进人流里  不要抬头
just get into that stream and don't look up.
我们只有一次机会
We got one shot.
那就让它成功吧
Let's make it count.
凯特尼斯 祝你好运
Good luck, Katniss.
谢谢你
Thank you.
波乐克斯
Pollux.
（我们一定会再见面的）
底格里斯 谢谢你为我们所做的一切
Tigris, thank you for everything you've done.
凯特尼斯 让我跟你一起行动 好吗
Katniss, let me come with you, okay?
我可以作为诱饵吸引他们的注意力...I can be a good distraction
that they know I'm...
不 我不想再失去你一次了
No, I'm not losing you again.
你和我们待在一起很安全
You'll be safer with us.
要是政府军搜查这些屋子 如果他被抓住了...What if peacemakers are searching
the houses, and if he's captured...
那就给我一个自杀药丸 我不怕死
Then, give me a nightlock pill, okay.I'm not going back.
答应我好好活着
Stay alive.
下次再见面的时候 就是新的世界了
If I see you again, it's going to be a different world.
凯特尼斯 我们出发吧
Alright, Katniss?
走吧
Let's go.
按照斯诺总统的命令
By order of President Snow,
所有难民必须前往总统官邸避难
all residents must proceed to the presidential estate.
请各位有秩序的向前行进
Please continue to move forward in a calm and orderly fashion.
到达后会有人发放饮用水 药物和衣物
Additional food, medicine and clothing will be provided upon arrival.
按照斯诺总统的命令
By order of President Snow,
所有难民必须前往总统官邸避难
all residents must proceed to the presidential estate.
请各位有秩序的向前行进
Please continue to move forward in a calm and orderly fashion.
到达后会有人发放饮用水 药物和衣物
Additional food, medicine and clothing will be provided upon arrival.
按照斯诺总统的命令
By order of President Snow,
所有难民必须前往总统官邸避难
all residents must proceed to the presidential estate.
请各位有秩序的向前行进
Please continue to move forward in a calm and orderly fashion.
到达后会有人发放饮用水 药物和衣物
Additional food, medicine and clothing will be provided upon arrival.
叛军来袭
It's the Rebels!
别动
Don't move!
攻击叛军
Rebels!
妈妈 妈妈
Mama! Mama!
快过去
Come on!
快
Come on.
杀了我
Shoot me!
保持镇定 把您的孩子送到前面来
Stay calm.Bring your children forward.
大门会定期打开
The gates will open momentarily.
我们会优先接纳儿童
The children will be received first.
保持镇定 把您的孩子送到前面来
Stay calm.Bring your children forward.
大门会定期打开
The gates will open momentarily.
我们会优先接纳儿童
The children will be received first.
保持镇定 把您的孩子送到前面来
Stay calm.Bring your children forward.
大门会定期打开
The gates will open momentarily.
我们会优先接纳儿童
The children will be received first.
那是都城军的飞机
It's the Capitol.
医生
Medic!
大夫
- 这里有伤员  - 快来破拆大门
- Medic! - Make a hole!
医生来了
Medics coming in.
拿个担架来
Bring a stretcher!
普瑞姆
Prim.
Primrose.
普瑞姆
Prim!
嘿 我要你躺好
Hey.I need you to lie back.
你没事 一切都会好的
You're okay.Everything's going to be okay.
都城军的飞机在官邸门口投下炸弹后战斗就结束了
The fight was over after that Capitol dropped those bombs at the feet of the palace.
起义军直接攻进去了
The rebels walked right in.
凯特尼斯 别乱动
Don't, Katniss.The only one's working.
每个人都感受到了炸弹的冲击力
Everybody felt it.
有些政府军、宫殿守卫的孩子也在人群中
Peacemakers. Palace Guards.They had kids in there too.
都被炸死
It was...
没几个人幸存下来
It was over after that.
妈
Mom.
我还记得我第一次带你来这的时候
I remember the first time I brought you here.
我们当时来过这
And here we are.
我把你的随身物品都带来了
I've brought all your things.
那你先收拾一下
Well, I'll leave you to get settled.
您好女士 我不能让您进去
Sorry, ma'am.I can't let you pass.
让她进去
Let her in.
我授权的
On my authority.
她有进去查看的资格
She has a right to anything behind that door.
那朵白玫瑰不错
That's a nice one.
多么纯洁的白色啊
The colors are lovely, of course,
然而某些人暗中的勾当要比这花肮脏的多
but nothing says perfection like white.
我就知道你会来的
I was hoping you'd find your way here.
我有很多事情想与你探讨一番
There are so many things we should discuss.
但我有预感我们这次的见面时间不会太长 所以
But I have a feeling your visit will be brief. So,
先说重要的事情
first things first.
首先我对你妹妹的去世感到十分遗憾
I wanted to tell you how very sorry I am about your sister.
她的死本来是可以避免的
So wasteful, so unnecessary.
明眼人都知道那时大局已定
Anyone could see the game was over by that point.
事实上 在他们扔下那些炸弹时我正准备签署官方投降令
In fact, I was just about to issue an official surrender when they released those parachutes.
明明是都城军扔下了这些炸弹
You released those parachutes.
你真的觉得我会下这样的命令?
You really think I gave the order?
我们都清楚我一定不会伤害儿童
We both know I'm not above killing children,
我不会毫无目的的杀戮
but I'm not wasteful.
我的杀戮都是有特殊目的的
I take life for specific reasons.
试问我为什么要杀掉这么多都城的孩子
And there was no reason for me to destroy a pen full of Capitol children.
我完全没有这么做的必要
None at all.
不得不承认科因的这步棋真是高明
I must concede it was a masterful move on Coin's part.
她让大家认为我轰炸那些无助的儿童只是为了抵挡住叛军的脚步
The idea that I was bombing our own helpless children to hold back the Rebels.
我的卫兵因此倒戈相向
It turned the last of my guards against me.
所以他们一枪没放就攻占了都城和我的宅邸
There was no resistance left inside the Capitol or the mansion.
你难道不知道战斗的过程是全程直播的吗?
Did you know it aired live?
这个方法真是十分巧妙啊 不是吗?
There's a...particular savvy in that, isn't there?
我知道她不是故意夺去你妹妹的生命的
I'm sure she wasn't gunning for your sister, but...
但这些事的的确确的发生了
These things happen in war.
我的失误在于没能早点猜到科因的意图
My failure was being so slow to grasp Coin's plan.
她让都城和其它区自相残杀
She let the Capitol and the districts destroy one another,
然后她登台掌控大权 我终于明白了她的计划
and she step in to take power over Thirteen, I see.
要是我没想错的话
But make no mistake.
她现在想替代我 当上总统
She intends to take my place now.
但我一直以来注意力都集中在你身上
But, I've been watching you.
你也只想一心杀了我
And you watching me.
恐怕我们都上当了
I'm afraid we have both been played for fools.
我不相信你
I don't believe you
噢我亲爱的艾佛丁小姐
Oh, my dear Miss Everdeen.
我想我们以前承诺过绝不对对方说谎吧
I thought we had agreed never to lie to each other.
科因总统想见你
President Coin ask for you.
你怎么这么久才来看我
You never came to see me.
- 我本想早点来的 - 那飞机是起义军的吗?
- I wanted to.- Was it ours?
是我们扔下的炸弹吗?
The bomb?
延时的爆炸?
The delayed explosion.
这是一个陷阱
The trap.
延时爆炸是为了让更多的人掉进这个陷阱
To draw more people in.
这是起义军安排好的吗?
Is that you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道的是
All I know is,
我本应该照顾好你的家人
I'm suppose to take care of your family.
对不起 我没能办到
And I'm sorry I couldn't.
在竞技场里你谁都保护不了
You can't protect anyone in an Arena.
盖尔 你走吧
Goodbye, Gale.
这是什么情况
What's this?
这些是幸存下来的胜利者. 来一起开个会吧
The remaining Victors.Won't you join us?
邀请你们来这开会有几个目的 首先
I've invited you all here for several reasons, but first...
我宣布
I have an announcement.
我光荣的成为了
I am taking the burden
帕纳姆国的临时总统
and the honor of declaring myself interim President of Panem.
临时的?
Interim?
这个临时的时间段大概有多长
Exactly how long is that interim?
这个恐怕不太好说
We have no way of knowing for certain.
大家也都知道现在社会还比较动荡
But, it's clear that people are far too emotional
民众难以做出理性的决定
right now to make a rational decision.
当时机成熟了我们会举行选举的
We'll plan an election when the time is right.
我叫你们来是因为有一个更重要的事情需要决定
But I've called you here for a far more important vote.
我们会进行象征性的投票表决
A symbolic vote.
今天下午我们将处决斯诺
This afternoon we will execute Snow.
和他的百余名同党
Hundreds of his accomplices also await their deaths.
包括一些都城的官员 守卫 政府军士兵
Capitol officials, peacekeepers torturers, gamemakers.
但问题来了 一旦我们开了这个头
But the danger is once we begin
起义军复仇的欲望就会一发不可收拾
the rebels will not stop calling for retribution.
民众会变得嗜血
Thirst for blood is a difficult urge to satisfy.
所以 我这提供一个备选项
So...I offer an alternative plan.
四人同意即通过该提议 不能弃权
A majority of four may approve it.No one may abstain.
我的提议如下
The proposal is this.
我们可以象征性的举办一个饥饿游戏
In lieu of these barbaric executions,
来代替野蛮的行刑过程
we hold a symbolic Hunger Games.
你又想逼迫都城的孩子进行一场饥饿游戏?
You want to have another Hunger Games with the Capitol's children?
- 你在逗我吗? - 我是认真的
- You're joking? - Not in the slightest.
这是普鲁塔克的点子吗?
Is this Plutarch's idea?
这是我的提议
It was mine.
这既满足了公众复仇的欲望
It balances the need for revenge with the least loss of human life.
- 你们可以开始投票了 - 我反对
- You may cast your votes.- No.
我坚决反对 这个想法太疯狂了
No, obviously not.This is crazy.
不 我觉得这样挺公平 斯诺自己有个孙女
No, I think it's more than fair.Snow's got a granddaughter.
我投赞成票
I say, yes.
我也赞成 让他们也尝尝痛苦的滋味
So do I.Let them have a taste of it.
你们要知道 正是我们这种复仇的想法引发了这场起义
You guys, this way of thinking is what started these uprisings.
我和皮塔一样 投反对票
I vote no, with Peeta.
如果芬尼克还活着 他也会反对的
So would Finnick if he were here.
不 他会赞成的 因为斯诺杀了他
No, he's not because Snow killed him.
我反对
No.
我们不应该将他们再视作敌人了
We need to stop viewing each other as enemies.
现在就看凯特尼斯和海米奇了
It's down to Katniss and Haymitch.
我要亲手杀了斯诺
I get to kill Snow.
我不会拦着你的
I expected no less of you.
那我投赞成票
Then I vote yes...
为了普瑞姆报仇
for Prim.
海米奇
Haymitch.
我和嘲笑鸟一样 投赞成票
I'm with the Mockingjay.
提议通过 好极了
That carries the vote.Excellent.
行刑结束后 我会宣布这项提案
I'll announce the games tonight after the execution.
马上就打扮好了
Bound to be quite the show.
噢 你看起来真是可爱
Oh, you look lovely, isn't she?
真是美丽极了
So beautiful.
打扮好啦
Finishing touches.
欢迎来到崭新的帕纳姆国
Welcome to the new Panem.
今天我们站在贡品大道上
Today, on the avenue of the tributes.
所有自由的帕纳姆们
All of Panem a free Panem
都将目睹这一幕
will watch more than a mere spectacle.
我们将见证一个伸张正义的历史时刻
We are gathered to witness a historic moment of justice.
今天 在这场革命中我们最重要的伙伴
Today, the greatest friend of the revolution,
将射出那一箭 它将结束所有战争
will fire the shot to end all wars.
愿她的力量象征着暴君专政的终结
May her powers signify the end of tyranny
象征着一个新纪元的开端
and the beginning of a new era.
嘲笑鸟 愿你心灵纯净 目光坚定
Mockingjay, may your aim be as true as your heart is pure.
哈哈哈
Eh- ha- ha...
不
No.
- 杀了他
- Kill him! - Kill him!
杀了他
Kill him!
凯特尼斯 我这么跟你说吧 你没让我失望
I'll say this for you, Katniss.You don't disappoint.
普鲁塔克让我带一封信给你
Well, Plutarch gave me a letter for you.
我不想看
I don't want it.
拜托 你能不能正常一点
You never make it easy, do you?
好吧 我来读给您老听
Okay.I'll read it for you.
凯特尼斯 可能所有的帕纳姆都为你这一箭感到震惊
Katniss, maybe the country was shocked tonight by your arrow,
但话说回来 也没那么令人惊讶
but once again I was not.
我早就预料到你会这么做
You're exactly what I believe you were.
我真希望能当面向你道个别 但现在科因和斯诺都死了
I wish I could give you a proper good bye but with both Coin and Snow dead,
今晚我们将开会决定这个国家未来的命运 我没法抽空去见你
the fate of the country will be decided tonight and I can't be seen at your side.
12个区的领导人将举行一个自由的选举
Tonight, the 12 district leaders will call for a free election.
毋庸置疑 佩勒会当上总统 她是一个有理性的人
There's no doubt that Paylor will carry she's become the voice of reason.
很抱歉你又要身担重负
I'm sorry so much burden fell on you.
但我知道你会直面这些困难
I know you'll never escape it.
为了这个国家的未来
But if I had to put you through it again
很抱歉我要暂时将你保护起来
for this outcome.I would.
战争已经结束了
The war is over.
我们现在处在一个相对稳定的阶段
We're in that sweet period where everyone agrees
不用再像以前一样担惊受怕
not to repeat the recent horrors.
当然 我们人类总是反复无常 愚蠢至极
Of course, we are fickle stupid beings
总是忘记过去 经常自相残杀
with poor memories and a great gift for self- destruction.
也许经过这场战争 我们才能学会许多
Although who knows? Maybe this time we'll learn.
送你出都城时我会亲自保证你的安全
I've secured you a ride out of the capital.
现在你最好远离公众视野
It's better for you to be out of sight.
时机成熟时 佩勒指挥官会赦免你的
But when the time is right Commander Paylor will pardon you.
这个国家终于获得了和平
The country will find it's peace.
希望你的心境也能平和下来 普鲁塔克
And I hope you can find yours.Plutarch.
现在去哪
What now?
回家 我们回家
Home.We go home.
我得好好和你道个别才能放你走
I couldn't let you go without a proper goodbye.
凯特尼斯 你要好好照顾自己
It's your job to take care of yourself now, Katniss.
向我保证你会找到它
Promise me you'll find it.
找到什么?
Find what?
属于胜利者的生活方式
The life of a Victor.
- 再见 - 再见 孩子
- Goodbye.- Goodbye, my girl.
别把自己变成一个陌生人
And you don't be a stranger.
- 照顾好她 - 我会的
- Take care of her.- I will.
她死了
She's gone.
走开
Get out.
滚出去
Get out!
普瑞姆死了
Prim is gone! Prim is gone!
她死了 永远都不会回来了
She's dead and she's not coming back!
滚出去
Get out! Get out!
皮塔
Peeta.
嗨
Hey.
你回家了
You came home.
是啊
Yeah.
这是我从森林边摘的
I found these...off by the edge of the forest.
报春花
It's Primrose.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
有些好消息告诉你们
You'll be happy to hear that
凯特妮斯的母亲正在都城培训新医生
Katniss'mother has been training new medical units in the Capitol.
盖尔被提拔为二区的区长
Gale has been promoted to a Captain in District 2
维护二区的秩序和安全
to help keep order and security.
我享受与我的儿子在一起的每分每秒
And I'm loving every moment with my son.
看到他总是让我想起他的爸爸
He reminds me everyday of his father.
我们都承受了太多苦难 但是那些苦难会激励我们
We all suffer so much.But we owe it to their memories
和我们的孩子们更坚强、更健康地生活下去
and to our children to do our best with these lives.
我希望大家都能过上平静的生活
I hope we both find in some peace.
安妮
Annie.
我郑重宣誓 尽我最大的力
I solemnly swear to the best of my ability
来捍卫每个帕纳姆公民的权利
to preserve, protect and uphold the rights of every citizen at Panem.
又是普鲁塔克写的演讲稿吧 这风格我太熟悉了
There's Plutarch brand,I know it all.
那句话是怎么说来着:"政治舞台真是瞬息万变啊"
What are their saying no one ever wins the games.
你爱我
You love me.
我说的对吗?
Real or not real?
你说得对
Real.
你做噩梦了吗?
Did you have a nightmare?
我也会做噩梦
I have nightmares too.
有一天 我会向你解释
Someday, I'll explain it to you.
为什么它们会出现
Why they came.
为什么它们永远挥之不去
Why they won't ever go away.
而且我会告诉你我是如何度过那些难熬的日子的
But I'll tell you how I survived it.
我会记住
I make a list in my head,
每一个人做过的每一件好事
for all the good things I've seen someone do.
即使它们微不足道
Every little thing I can remember.
这就像一个游戏
It's like a game.
我一遍遍地玩
I do it over and over.
以至于这些年有点乏味了 但
after all these years, but...
生活是场更艰难的游戏
There are much worse games to play.